## SARAH JAYNE CATION

### PERFORMANCE MARKETING PROFESSIONAL

# CONTACT ☐ 07505983923 ☐ sarah.cation@ntlworld.com ☐ LinkedIn ☐ London, United Kingdom

# PROFILE & QUALITIES

An ambitious and proactive marketing professional with 5+ years of experience in CRM and an MSc. in International Fashion Marketing.

Thrives in a demanding environment and is highly resilient with a strong commercial acumen. A strong leader who coaches a motivated team to implement successful campaigns. Balances considerable pressure across a multitude of projects while delivering results.

- Confident in Excel, Tableau, Mailchimp, DotDigital, Ometria and Google Analytics
- Takes a customer-centric approach balanced with business goals, KPIs and commercials
- · Data driven, analytical and strategic
- Organised with strong time management and an ability to prioritise effectively
- A confident leader with an ability to influence and prolific in stakeholder management

-----

### EDUCATION

### Level 5 Leadership & Management

Corndel (Chartered Management Institute) 2023 - present

IDM Award in Behavioural Economics (85%) Institute of Data & Marketing 2020

MSc International Fashion Marketing (Merit) Glasgow Caledonian University 2016-2017

**BA (Hons) Business Studies (2:1)** Glasgow Caledonian University 2012-2016

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **CRM Manager**

### **THG Ingenuity (London)**

March 2022 - Present

Leads a team of 3, responsible for delivering the CRM strategy (email, SMS) focused on acquisition, retention, converting prospects, driving recency, and increasing the CLTV.

- Has a remit of 15+ clients in the fashion industry, spanning global clients with a presence in multiple locales, to those launching in new territories with little brand awareness.
   Manages databases ranging from 0 contacts at launch to those with 900,000 contacts.
- Analyses all CRM performance and presents weekly/monthly/quarterly reports to key internal and external stakeholders. Takes a data first approach to identify any opportunities to optimise campaigns, drive revenue and channel participation.
- Identifies core customer groups, develops 'personas' and bespoke customer lifecycle segmentation models to target customers with relevant comms at the right time (Berghaus saw 34% of prospects convert into customers since implementation).
- Lead the implementation of hyper personalised comms through rolling out CRM Profile Builders across clients to gather preferences data. Combined this with purchase and behavioural data to increase CTOR by 56% and CVR by 20% on average across all clients. The success of this project was acknowledged within THG Ingenuity and rolled out across Nestle and Homebase.
- Develops and launches bespoke loyalty programmes across different clients (No.7 US saw a 47% increase in revenue YoY, through a tiered loyalty programme).
- Works closely with Ecommerce and Trading teams to drive channel opportunities, growth and deliver brand campaigns.
- Enhanced ways of working with siloed marketing channel teams through a regular diarised catch up to discuss key projects, wins and learnings. Identifies opportunities to drive omnichannel activity during these catch ups.
- Cultivates a motivated team who are encouraged to innovate e.g. through test and learn
  programmes. Dedicated to personal development for myself, direct reports and colleagues;
  completed an internal Leadership programme and is a mentor.

### **Brand Manager (CRM & Partnerships)**

### ASK Italian - Azzurri Group (London)

November 2019 - March 2022

Responsible for the delivery of a clear omni-channel marketing strategy aligned across all touchpoints, from digital to physical restaurant. Manages the CRM strategy, brand comms and promotional activity.

- Optimised ASK Perks loyalty programme and increased participation by 19% YoY.
- Implemented a digital acquisition strategy through website optimisation and Google Ads; achieved pre-pandemic growth level of a 2% increase in database contacts MoM.
- Upgraded and optimised multi-channel workflows across all user lifecycle stages
- Measures performance of channels and campaigns, analyses reports and implements optimisation recommendations.
- Identified an opportunity to enhance database sign ups by including a QR code on reusable menus and acquired 9% more contacts in the first month.
- Collaborated with the Finance and Food teams to identify opportunities to drive AOV while
  protecting profit margin. One promo resulted in 366% increase in Deliveroo orders.
- Had full ownership of the CRM strategy, from content creation, A/B testing, segmentation.
   to create engaging emails that convert, deliver above industry benchmark KPIs and align with commercial priorities of the business.

### **Campaign Strategy Executive**

### 4ICG Group (Glasgow)

March 2018 - March 2022

Responsible for delivering B2B digital marketing campaigns across including email, paid and organic social. In March 2019, I was promoted to Campaign Strategy Executive (from Digital Marketing Executive), taking the lead on developing and executing marketing strategies for global clients, including Google and Microsoft.

- Produced marketing emails, A/B testing plans, content creation and data management.
- Proactively enhanced current processes; created and launched an email workflows to nurture customers from acquisition to conversion.
- Delivered weekly and monthly reports on platform growth, engagement KPIs and optimisation recommendations.
- Analysed market reports and consumer trends to inform campaign strategies
- Fulfilled client briefs with tailored proposals, ensured all activities aligned across various channels and delivered on time according to project plans